<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on WangScape</title>
        <link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/post/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on WangScape</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:31:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>P1004 [NOIP 2000 improvement group] grid score analysis and summary</title>
        <link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/p1004-noip-2000-improvement-group-grid-score-analysis-and-summary/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 11:31:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/p1004-noip-2000-improvement-group-grid-score-analysis-and-summary/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a classic but difficult chessboard model problem. Although it is a NOIP problem in 2000, it is still quite difficult for first-time contacts like me as the finale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Look at the background of the question first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NOIP 2000 improvement group T4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Question description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a square diagram of N × N (N ≤ 9), some of which we fill in positive integers, while others put the number 0.
Someone starts at point A (0, 0) in the top left corner of the diagram and can walk down or to the right until they reach point B (N, N) in the bottom right corner.On the way he walks, he can take the number in the square (which becomes the number 0).
This person walked from point A to point B twice, trying to find 2 such paths, so that the sum of the obtained numbers is the maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Date input format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first line of the input is an integer N (representing the grid diagram of N × N), the next line has three integers, the first two represent the position, and the third number is the number put on the position. A separate line of 0 indicates the end of the input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just output an integer representing the maximum sum obtained on the 2 paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sample input/output&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masukkan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 3 13&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2 6 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 5 7&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 4 14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 2 21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 6 4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6 3 15&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;= 7×2 = 14)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 0 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Output
67&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructions/Tips&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data range: 1 ≤ N ≤ 9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I initially tried to enumerate the matrix that had been changed (that is, simulated) again after a round of enumeration, but found that the difficulty was a little too great. Finally, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of a solution, so I found Claude. The solution it gave was to use the dp algorithm (see method 1 for details). I also thought of the algorithm of DFS combined with pruning (thank you for the maze problem I did before, it is an algorithm problem related to the minimum number of steps, which is just suitable for DFS combined with pruning) (see method 2 for details). Later, Claude also gave an algorithm that is suitable for general solutions - the cost flow solution method (too difficult, belonging to the hyper-schema solution method, sketching one or two, see method 3 for details).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ps. Explain why two enums cannot be taken. One path changes the map, affecting the second, so the two paths must be considered in conjunction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution 1 (dp dynamic programming):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core idea: Advance both paths simultaneously and simulate two people walking at the same time with one DP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State design: set dp [k] [x1] [x2], where:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;k is the number of steps currently taken (i.e. the value of x + y, from 2 to 2N)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x1 and x2 are the line numbers where the two people are currently located.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By k and x can be derived y = k - x (key, this step reduces the dimension), so the column number does not need to be stored separately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deduplication: When two people are in the same cell (x1 = = x2, then y1 = = y2), the cell is taken only once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transfer: Two people each can choose to move to the right or down for a total of 4 combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full Code
__ code_block_0 __\ n\ n&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time complexity: O (N ³)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution 2 (DFS + pruning):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core idea: Similar to the dp algorithm (after all, deep search and dp are essentially one thing), but adds the step of memorized search, avoiding repetitive searches. (If there is no memory search, the amount of calculation will be an exponential explosion, about 4 ^ 16 times at N = 9)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full code __ code_block_1 __\ n\ n&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time complexity: O (N ³)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solution 3 (Cost Flow Solution):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core idea: Convert &amp;ldquo;maximizing the two paths&amp;rdquo; into a network flow problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modeling Ideas
Key Observations:
Two paths from A to B = 2 flows from source to sink
Fetch at most once per cell = 1 capacity per node
Get number max = cost max (min to min)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Split point: Each grid (i, j) is split into two nodes in and out:
in → out: Capacity 1, Cost -map [i] [j] (minimize costs by minimizing costs)
in → out: add one more capacity 1, cost 0 (allow the second path to go through but do not take repeated values)
Namely: Consolidated to Capacity 2, but only the first unit stream has revenue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connected edges: (i, j) out connects (i +1, j) in and (i, j +1) in, capacity 2, cost 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source sink: The source point S is connected to (1,1) .in, (N, N) .out is connected to the sink point T, and the traffic is 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After splitting each grid (i, j):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capacity 1, cost-val (first way through, take the number)
in (i, j) = = = = = = = = = = = = = = = = &amp;gt; out (i, j)
Capacity 1, cost 0 (second way through, number taken)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full code (MCMF, SPFA implementation) __ code_block_2 __\ n\ n&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time complexity: O (E · SPFA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantage: Easily scales to K paths.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hello and welcome to my blog</title>
        <link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/hello-and-welcome-to-my-blog/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 13:28:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/hello-and-welcome-to-my-blog/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly a day of half a day of self-doubt, half a day of fighting with AI (doge), and a whole day of using your head and table harder than anyone else&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;January 21, 2026 finally became an extraordinary day for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal blog is finally live!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will record my learning experience on my blog, occasionally complain, and even occasionally write a book review (and even record some of my favorite poems)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will record the difficulties I have encountered in programming, the harvest, and a summary of some knowledge points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog might also be my all-disciplinary notebook? (University Only)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Although I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can maintain my blog all the time, after all, it&amp;rsquo;s lazy, do your best)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I will also record some other things, not only in terms of code, but also in terms of artificial intelligence? Algorithmic? Or, in terms of gaming?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, music? Movies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will do my best to make blogging learning-oriented, hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope my update frequency is not too low&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it, it&amp;rsquo;s time to continue fixing the bug&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(ps. Now the blog is still rough, it will be better in the future!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edited February 3, 2026&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Site Repair Summary</title>
        <link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/site-repair-summary/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:14:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/site-repair-summary/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed the animation carton problem in the lower left column;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed the problem of switching between the Chinese and English interfaces;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed the problem of avatar display;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed the problem of counting function and solved the problem of calling Umami API;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched WSwriter, a website article writing and pushing assistant, to meet the needs of writing in the office-like interface without the IDE interface, supporting one-click preview, submission, modification, and deletion of articles, as well as inserting code, images, and tables;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Added commenting function;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed the error of double quotes when adding tags to WSwriter;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security of the website has been maintained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
