<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on WangScape</title><link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on WangScape</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:39:21 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hello, and Welcome to My Blog!</title><link>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/hello-and-welcome-to-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:39:21 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://w2343419-del.github.io/WangScape/en/p/hello-and-welcome-to-my-blog/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After spending half a day in self-doubt, another half-day wrestling with AI, and a full day testing whether my head or my desk is harder&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;January 21st, 2026, has finally become a day to remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal blog is officially live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to use this space to document my learning journey, vent a little when things get tough, and occasionally share book reviews or even some of my favorite poetry when inspiration strikes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, you’ll find:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Study Notes: Summaries of key concepts and breakthroughs in my coding journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic Archive: This might even evolve into a comprehensive notebook for all my university subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life &amp;amp; Hobbies: Beyond the technical stuff, I might dive into Artificial Intelligence, algorithms, or even my interests in gaming, music, and movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll do my best to keep this blog focused on learning—at least, that’s the plan! Though I’ll admit I can be a bit lazy sometimes, I’m committed to maintaining this space as much as I can. I just hope my update frequency doesn&amp;rsquo;t drop too low&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s all for now. It’s time to go back and squash the remaining bugs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(P.S. The site is still a bit rough around the edges, but I promise it’ll get better over time!)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>